Lindley Family mss., 1670-1874 LMC 2866
Lilly Library
Lindley Family mss.
1670-1874
Lilly Library
Lindley, Charles W., 1846-1941
Lindley, Marian (Towel)
LMC 2866
4 Boxes
1 folio
1 folio oversize
The Lindley Family mss., 1670-1874, consist of photographs, letters, diaries, records, and genealogical material of Charles W. Lindley and the Lindley family.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2015
Biographical Note
Charles W. Lindley, 1846-1941, was born in Fountain County, Indiana to Aaron and Juli Ann Lindley. Lindley enlisted in the 116th Regiment, Company C of the Union Army on July 1, 1863 as a private, and was mustered out in Lafayette, Indiana on March 1, 1864. He later moved to Parke County and joined the Rush Creek Weekly Meeting Quaker group, working as a farmer and marrying Marian (Towel) Lindley in 1872.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of large framed photographs of Charles W. Lindley in Civil War uniform as well as a large paper wheel of family genealogy. Also included is a collection of letters and diaries, diary transcriptions, and navy mercantile records pertinent to the family's history.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged following original order.
Indiana--History; United States --History --Civil War, 1861-1865
- Diary
  - April 10, 1868 - June 2, 1868 (Box 1)
  - November 20, 1870 - August 1, 1872 (Box 1)
  - March 24, 1879 - May 16, 1879 (Box 1)
- Scrimshaw (Box 2)
- Notes and Clippings (Box 2)
- Journal Transcriptions (Box 2)
- The Y2K Lindley Family Archive (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - 1863 (Box 2)
  - 1864 (Box 2)
  - 1865 (Box 2)
  - 1866 (Box 2)
  - 1867-1914 (Box 2)
- Ribbon, cloth doily (Box 3)
- Framed Photographs (Box 4)
- Genealogy chart (Ovflat 32)
- "Presentation of a medal to Mr. Clay" (broadside), 10 February 1852 (Foliobox 29)